hello everyone uh before we get into our
magic product review today let's go
ahead and play a quick fiddle tune
all right that's it i have to admit i
wish i could tell you what the name of
that tune is but i flipped on the camera
just started playing and i honestly
don't remember what the name of that
tune is anyway welcome to the channel
everyone if you don't know who i am i'm
fiddling johnny and this is my fiddle
channel and magic product review
and today
i am reviewing yigal musica's spider pen
x
and i am going to be unfiltered today on
this one and just give it to you
straight on what i think about this
product so stick around and we'll get
right into it
[Music]
hello everyone and welcome back to the
channel
always grateful that you are here
all right we're gonna do the spider-pen
x today
and i'm going to break all the rules
around reviews you know look these are
designed where you should hang out to
the very end where i give you the juicy
stuff at the end so you stay for the
whole thing and i want you to stay for
the whole thing
but i'm going to give you my conclusion
right up front because i can't control
myself
um and i don't i think this is the first
time on the channel where i've really
just come out and said
avoid this product
usually i'll sort of say something's
like oh some people might like this um
i'm just gonna say i would probably say
stay away from the spider pen x i'm not
recommending it all right
there right now you go watch the next
review now stick around so you get to
hear my entire thoughts on this um
what the heck is this so this is a
utility device and what it does is it
allows you
to be able to float objects and move
light objects it is an itr and invisible
thread reel the invisible thread reel is
inside here and i'm going to bring it up
close so that you can really see this
all right and hopefully that will focus
quickly the pin is just
beautiful it is a nice
very professional
looking pen there
and up here i'm just going to show you
how it works
it has a spool thread in the top here
and if i take my
wax i just broke the wax as i pulled it
can you believe that
okay see there's that just immediately
goes to the issue
why i
it should not break when i'm just
freaking pulling it out
i mean
that's just annoying so all right
uh hopefully i was gonna demo a little
more for you but that's it that's all
you're getting there
for that so uh what is it so it allows
you to float objects okay uh and move
light objects uh real on the inside of a
pen
um
all right i'll get into the details
about why i don't like it here in a
second but let's talk about what do you
get so in this box
you're gonna get this pin all right and
the pen also is going to come with a one
quadruple a battery that will run the
motor inside here and make the chip
that's inside here the motherboard work
inside of this pin right here you're
also going to get a spool of invisible
thread that lives in the top here and it
is 40 feet in length or if you're using
the metrics it's 12 meters that's a lot
of a lot of thread in there which is
awesome
you're also going to get a one
streaming slash downloadable vimeo video
that is 44 minutes in length so that's
what you're getting
let's talk about how the instructions
are
and then we'll talk about the utility
device itself so how are the
instructions well there's good and bad
here the good part is is that it is
probably the slickest nicest looking
tutorial out there on the market hands
down i think ego musica
really just does some beautiful quality
look editing
polish on his tutorials above all others
so that's the nice stuff
the downside
on the tutorial you get all the stuff
you should expect to get like you're
going to get um some live performances
you're going to walk through how does it
work and the setup for your device um
the sort of stuff that you can expect
he's going to go through the stuff that
that i thought was really good in terms
of how to attach the wax to your
invisible thread
i've always sort of done it my own
certain way he has a very specific way
he does which i thought was an
improvement and better and i liked it
so that part was uh really good he'll
also talk about what you might expect
about what are the limitations with
invisible thread like what are your
lighting restrictions and clothing
restrictions those sorts of things he's
going to run you through a couple of
routines
he's going to go through a floating bill
a walking bill and a balancing bills
routines and he's going to also go
through what you saw there on the if you
watched the teaser for the product where
it's called relief and he
leaf
puts itself back on a tree uh which i'm
not sure where you would ever use that
in practicalness it does look beautiful
to be honest uh and i guess it's really
there to inspire you to think about how
you might use uh an invisible thread
reel that is right here in your pen
um the parts that i uh
didn't really work for me is that at a
hundred dollar i'm spending a hundred us
dollars for this i expect something a
little bit more than sort of like those
four routines i think anyone who has
used invisible thread knows the floating
bill knows how to do a floating bill
especially with an itr so there's
nothing new there i think the walking
bill is not really that new as well
the relief is new and i think the
balancing one is new uh but at this
price point i kind of expect more
routines the other thing that i didn't
get on here is that i want real life
experience and that all of us who have
used invisible thread know that our
thread breaks so what do you do in a
live performance when your thread breaks
do you have an out that you use on the
routines that you use when you have
breakage what is your out can you show
that to us
none of that
which i think is a real problem at this
price point to be honest and i think for
anyone who's purchasing invisible thread
and you're going at what i would say
high this is higher end i expect to hear
at least a mention of that so i think
the tutorial overall was really lacking
even on the performances we don't sort
of see him getting into the performance
we don't see him sort of doing the
cleanup on the performance he'll talk
through that some
at the end but we don't see that in live
performance i want to see that uncut
what it really looks like in your setup
and that sort of stuff for the real
world um it lacked it should be there
and it's not there
um all right so let's talk about the pen
itself so you already saw it up close a
little bit uh i feel like the pen itself
is a high quality nice pen that's a real
pen that your spectators could use or
you could use yourself
um
but the problems with it is that i found
the thread itself
is uh
breaks really easily
at a higher level than just about any
other thread i've used in the past and i
know people really like eagle music's
thread i myself use loops all the time
and have for
just as i think as long as loops have
been out i mean as long as i can
remember um and i don't find the same
level of breakage on those as i did on
this
so i didn't find
the thread to be
good enough
quite simple
also when the thread breaks because the
motor continues to run
to recoil your thread it can get tangled
up in here i've had that problem i spent
three days ago my thread broke i spent
and i'm not exaggerating to make a point
here because i timed it because i was
curious i spent two hours
trying to find the end of my damn thread
on my spool to be able to
do you know practice again uh two hours
is ridiculous and maybe that's an
outlier uh no my thread has broken so
many times on this and that uh i feel
like i'm spending an inordinate amount
of time um trying to find the thread
again and reattach the thread and i
meant to bring it for this video i have
the this headgear magnifying glass uh
that i use when i'm working with
invisible thread so that it's easy to
find and so i'm using this massive
magnifier
and with that still have challenges with
it i guess some folks will say well
that's an up it's really invincible
thread yeah but it shouldn't be that
invisible
so a problem with the tangling finding
the end on here higher than average
breakage um some folks might like it
i'll pretend i'm pulling it out i'm not
don't have anything there right now but
um
the tension on it this would be a good
thing i think overall is that the motor
runs when you pull out the thread which
creates tension on your string
i like that because i don't want my
object bouncing too much i i like it a
little bit strong so that is a good part
about this if you're able to overcome
the massive amount of breakage and i'm
not someone who is new to invisible
thread if you've been here before you
know that i post reviews of some other
products
i'm not green to it love invisible
thread
and i think i'm speaking from fair
experience here is that um just more
breakage than what is normal and it
takes a while if you're new to invisible
thread to sort of find what is the
limitations of your thread this
you know as you just saw i was pulling
out and it broke
i'm just pulling it out which should not
occur
um like if i was in a real professional
setting and that happened
well i immediately don't have to figure
out what am i going to do with this
panel why did i pull it out
and
find you know a use for that or i guess
if i didn't pull it out it's just
sitting here i know immediately like
okay whatever routine i was going into i
need to go into a different routine
all right um
i will say on the upside of the pen
because of the motor it's activated when
you pull it it stays active for 45
seconds when you uh have it retract it
automatically turns itself off after 45
seconds there's no buttons to turn it on
or off simply by pulling the string it
activates it there's a motor in here you
cannot hear the motor it is
really truly silent uh and that is an
upside um you can't hear it i could put
it up to my ear and barely hear it um
all right so
um just the thread breakage is just
ridiculous
on that if you really are going to
purchase this for 15 you can buy two
additional spools
and uh you should just have those ready
to pop in
as you go to whatever your next table or
however you're transitioning between
effects uh to be able to use it um if
you're trying to find it in real time
that's just not realistic and um it is a
non-starter um all right
let's talk a little about uh does it
lock no it doesn't lock is it loud no
it's not loud is the thread strong no
not strong
um is it easy to fix no i
yes technically it's easy to fix but is
incredibly time consuming
um how long will the battery last uh
igal masika says that it will last for
basically you should replace your
battery every six months and you expect
to get 50 performances out of um
the battery all right so i don't know
what that really means 50 performances
but
that's how he describes it
um all right i think i've already said
most of my pros and cons nice pen looks
great good technology and battery
breakage is horrible uh difficulty with
um tangling inside here and finding the
end of it once it gets retracted back in
here has been really hard
it's easy you pull it out you pull out
the spool and you look for it but i
found that really hard
um all right
also on the tutorial at 100 i expect you
to talk about
what happens in real life performances
with the routines that you have if your
string breaks and what are your outs all
right
costs
99.95 cents in the united states if you
want to get spool refills you can get
two school refills for 15
if you want to buy the black accessory
kit which cost 9.95
which means that the clip on here where
you clip it onto your shirt or your
jacket or your pocket if you want to get
that in black you can do so i think if
i'm spending a hundred dollars for to
get an additional black clip just
included in the product
i feel like i'm being nickeled and dimed
at this point you will get wax that
comes with it one little itty bitty
piece of wax you're going to need more
wax over time
i do use uh
yugo mesica's wax which cost you 9.95
cents and this will probably last me an
entire lifetime
all right my final thoughts are
um
if you've been using the spider pen
series and you like it and you want to
upgrade
maybe you consider it um i don't the
upgrades are
small
you know basically it's slimmer
goes for 45 seconds versus 30 seconds
i think that's about it to be honest
and you can do the same thing with much
more affordable products so i think if
you like the spider-pen pro series
spider-pan spider-pen spider-penix might
be for you you know how it works exactly
and you might like it
if you're looking for something i would
probably avoid this one to be honest
um if you're beginner in invisible
thread reels i'm going to make some
recommendations and none of these are
perfect either i like real sharp by ud
gore
and here is that it's a sharpie with the
exact same sort of functionality i've
got the invisible thread out i found
this invisible thread which he calls it
kevlar thread i think to be really
strong and durable and just as invisible
um it is analog there's no electronics
in this at all it doesn't mean that it's
perfect i have had tangling in mine and
spent a fair amount of time trying to
untangle at times but at twenty nine
dollars and ninety five cents
much cheaper than a hundred dollars you
might also consider for
twelve dollars again by udechat gore his
covert reel and this is just basically
the reel itself and you use magnets to
clip it underneath your clothing to be
able to use now i'm not
ude chad gore doesn't know that i'm
recommending those products at all and i
paid for those myself so um
those are sort of my recommendations uh
for other options i know folks will ask
in the comments what do you think is
better uh the tarantula versus this or
that um i don't have all of the
invisible threat products out there so i
don't know that i can answer all of
those
but those uh my thoughts here has
i would pass on this one so and i'm
sorry to say that to igal masika who i
know has put putting a lot of time and
effort into this product
and is working hard to make a living
with this stuff but if i'm going to be
honest with you guys um
i just didn't like it so and i want to
like it so all right there we are
i think that's it uh i hope this is
really helpful for you make sure that
you're leaving comments if you have any
of the spider-pen
series whether it's the newest one or
older ones and what your thoughts are
things that would be helpful for the
community to know if they're considering
it certainly i'm just one perspective
and other folks love the spider-pen x
out there
and so i know they love it for a reason
i just don't have that same experience
make sure you like i just really
appreciate it if you like it and
subscribe if you have not yet subscribed
all right everyone thank you so much for
being here i'm fiddling johnny and
remember to keep fiddling around with
your magic of stick around maybe i'll
show a demo i'll see you guys all next
time bye
all right let's put the spider-pen x
through some of its paces
uh
we're going to get the walking bill
which looks something like this
not very good with
you know
folding the bill up to be honest
but you're supposed to make it like a
little bit like a bow tie
like that there
and then
it's that on the back of your hand
and it will
should walk up and down
your arms there he goes
there we go
that is
your
walking bill
i hope that look good thank you for
watching wait let's do one more
floating bill
let's see
let's do something like that
get a little static electricity
and it will
just
rise up
i like that with floating bills like
this you can simply
do that
so you can see that there's no strings
attached
hope that's in frame all right
there you go
floating bill
all right i'm gonna do a quick uh demo
of the balancing bill act you're gonna
take two
uh pieces of currency and you're
basically going to challenge your
um
uh spectator to see if they can't
balance
a bill just like that on their hand
and then once you're able to balance
that bill on your hand you take it to a
whole another level and you're going to
go ahead and take a second bill
and balance that
on there as well
enough you can see that sideways anyway
that is the balancing bills
that you can do with your spider pen x
alright thanks for watching everyone
remember to hit that like button
subscribe and i'll see you all next time
bye
[Music]
you